

Arif Dwi Laksito, M. Kom

Lecturer at Department Informatics,
Faculty of Computer Science,
Universitas Amikom Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Summary

A lecturer at Universitas Amikom Yogyakarta, Indonesia who has a long list of professional experience in software engineering. He particularly enjoys collaborating with scientists from different disciplines to develop new skills and solve new challenges.

Profile

Nationality : Indonesian

Date of Birth : 29 Septermber 1982

Sex/Status : Male/Married

Email : arif.laksito@amikom.ac.id

Phone : +62-8562-926468

Skype : arif.laksito

Education and Course

Master's Degree

STMIK AMIKOM Yogyakarta, 2009-2013, Grade: 3.42 out of 4.00

Skills covered in IT Management, Information Systems

Bachelor's Degree

Department of Computer Science, Universitas Gadjah Mada (UGM)

2004 - 2006, Grade: 2.92 out of 4.00

Skills covered in Computer Science: Web Services, Data Mining and Artificial Intelligence

Associate Degree Diploma

STMIK AMIKOM Yogyakarta, 2001 – 2004, Grade: 3.59 out of 4.00

Skills covered in Software Engineering: Web Development, Database Management, Programming and

Algorithm

Certificate of completion course at Coursera & University of Minnesota

Sep 2020 - Recommender Systems: Matrix factorization and Advanced techniques.

Aug 2020 - Recommender Systems: Evaluation and Metrics.

Jul 2020 - Nearest Neighbor Collaborative Filtering.

Jun 2020 - Introduction to Recommender Systems: Non-Personalized and Content-Based.

Certificate of completion Java Fundamentals

Oracle Academy, Jakarta, Indonesia (March 2013)

Successfully completed 40 hours of professional development for the Java Fundamentals, Oracle Academy course

Certificate of completion Java Programming

Oracle Academy, Jakarta, Indonesia (Apr 2014)

Successfully completed 32 hours of professional development for Java Programming, Oracle Academy course

Google Faculty Development Program

Google Developers, Bandung, Indonesia (30 Jul – 3 Aug 2018)

Participated in the Faculty Development Program training about Android Development Expert by Dicoding Indonesia and Google Developers

Employment History

Lecturer at Faculty of Computer Science, Universitas Amikom Yogyakarta

Aug 2008 - Present

- · Conducting teaching, researching and community service
- Supervising student's research activity
- Writing research, papers and publications

System designer and Analyst at IC Dept AMIKOM Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Aug 2007 - Present

Responsible in Software division on Academic Information System in Universitas Amikom.

Web programmer at PT. TELKOM Indonesia

July 2006 - Aug 2007

Developed a dashboard application for executives and responsible for displaying a report in visual.

Honor and Award

Google Scholarship Development Program

- Scholarship for Indonesian Lecturer in 2018 (Batch 2)
- Excellence of completing e-course in Android programming and got free training in Bandung,
 Indonesia

Research Funding Grants from Indonesian Government

- 2018, research about analysis of drug interactions on social media
- 2017, research about GIS decision support system for waqf distribution
- 2016, research about synchronization method in web service & android app
- 2016, community service about ICT at Margokaton Sleman
- 2015, research about developing CMS on conference publication system

Language Ability

May 2021, International English Language Testing System (IELTS), held by IDP Jakarta. Overall score: 6.0 (Listening: 6.0, Reading: 5.5, Writing: 6.5, Speaking: 6.0)

Publication and Research

Evaluation of Backpropagation Neural Network Models for Early Prediction of Student's Graduation in XYZ University

- International Journal on Advance Science, Engineering and Information Technology, Vol.11 (2021) No.2
- Author: Ainul Yaqin, Arif Dwi Laksito, Siti Fatonah

The Comparison of Distance Measurement for Optimizing KNN Collaborative Filtering Recommender System

- IEEE, 2020 3rd International Conference on Information and Communications Technology
- Author: Zauvik Maruf, Arif Dwi Laksito

Apriori Algorithm Optimization using Temporary Table

- IEEE, 2019 International Conference on Information and Communications Technology
- Author: Arif Dwi Laksito, Kusrini

A Comparison Study of Search Strategy on Collecting Twitter Data for Drug Adverse Reaction

- IEEE, 2018 International Seminar on Application for Technology of Information and Communication
- Author: Arif Dwi Laksito, Kusrini, H Sismoro, F Rahmawati, M Yusa

GIS-Based Decision Support System for Cash Waqf Distribution

- Journal of Theoretical and Applied Information Technology, Vol.96 (2018) No.3
- Author: Kusrini, KC Kirana, M Purwanto, Arif Dwi Laksito

GIS technology selection for visualization of independent economic modelling of former Woman Migrant Worker (WMW)

- IEEE, 2017 5th International Conference on Cyber and IT Service Management (CITSM)
- Author: Kusrini, M Purwanto, KC Kirana, Arif Dwi Laksito

The Use of COBIT Framework to Analyze Maturity Model of Information Technology Governance in STMIK AMIKOM Yogyakarta

Master thesis, STMIK AMIKOM Yogyakarta, Indonesia, Dec 2012

Skills

- Strong communication/presentation skills
- Web programming using PHP, JavaScript.
- Android programming using Java and Kotlin.
- SQL Database Programming.
- Data Science programming using Python and R.